Humphrey Okoth

Kampala, Uganda (+256) 705-188046 humpasp@gmail.com https://github.com/humphreyokoth https://humphreyokoth.github.io/portfolio/

Summary

A software developer with a background in JavaScript libraries such as React, and frameworks like Express with Node Js, Next Js and PHP Codelgniter 4. Proficient in Agile methodologies and a wide range of technologies including Git, Github, Gitlab, WordPress theme and plugin development, CI/CD, CircleCI, Cucumber BDD, TDD, Jest,Mocha and Chai, Jira, Asana,Scrum, Python, Docker, Postgresql, SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, and Linux. Proven experience in delivering successful payment, health care, agrif intech projects, leading teams and an ability to adapt to new technologies and methodologies.

Skills

Git, Github, Gitlab, JavaScript, React with Typescript, ReactJs, Next JS, Redux, Jquery, Node JS, Nest Js, Codeigniter 4, WordPress, CI/CD, CircleCI, Leadership, Agile Project Management, Scrum, HTML /CSS, Cucumber BDD, TDD, Mocha and Chai, Jira, Asana, Trello, Python for data analysis, Python, Numpy, Pandas, Jupyter, Docker, PHP, Postgresql, SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Linux.

Experience

October 2022 - Present

Mcash, Kampala - Backend Developer

- Backend development using CodeIgniter 4 framework.
- Code optimization using object oriented programming.
- API integration with Cyclos payment gateway.
- Data encryption, database management with sql and Linux DevOps.
- Authentication and authorization using bearer tokens with help of building of the curl library for the authorization api.
- Creating a custom curl library for user authentication using JWT tokens.

July 2021 - October 2022

Kanzu Code, Kampala - Software Developer

- Wordpress plugin and theme development with php scripts, JQuery and JavaScript.
- Gathering and defining customer requirements, human centered design for development of a task scheduling web app using Nest JS and react with typescript.
- Agile methodology of using scrum, Jira for shippable products and time boxed tasks.
- Code optimization using object oriented programming for a church management system for different church activities and locations.

January 2021- PRESENT

Refactory, Kampala - Software developer

- Planned web development with agile methodology and scrum, converting mockups using figma into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, Ajax, Jquery.
- REST api development using Node JS for waste management system and testing using endpoints using postman.
- Mentoring of junior developers in python and JavaScript, Node Js to debug, communication and to build web applications.

January 2022 - June 2022

Upwork, United Kingdom - Backend Software developer (Node JS)

- REST API development using Node JS and Sequelize ORM for ecommerce platform.
- Endpoints for subscription and promotion offers, Stripe payment endpoint.
- Testing with postman and JEST endpoints for subscription, stripe.
- Razor payment integration for payment gateway endpoint.

June 2018 - January 2022

Orisa consult LLC, Wisconsin - Apprenticeship IT support

- Web presence planning, implementing changes and integrating requests.
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, CSS.

Education

January 2021 - December 2021

Clarke International University, Kampala - Certificate

Software Engineering.

August 2012 - September 2017

Makerere University, Kampala - Degree

Bachelor of Information Technology.

Awards

Cisco Networking Bootcamp Basic Switch and Router configurations 2022.

Refactory mentorship programme, Refactory Uganda 2022.

CertificateOfCompletion_JavaScript Code Challenges ,Linkedin 2022.

Leadership and software development certificate, Refactory.

Microsoft server associate certificate 2012 R2, Aptech computer education.

Digital marketing, Google Africa digital garage.

Google Africa developer training program, Google.